In this app, we see an example of a
defragmented network traffic that uses the big cookie model. All
the repeating transfers have been bundled together, and all
the intermittent transfers have been
largely replaced with aggressive prefetching.
Obviously, you usually can't entirely predict what data users
might need, nor can you ignore either client or service
site changes the need to be synchronized. You can
aim to minimize the number of radio state transitions through
a combination of aggressive prefetching in addition to batching
and queueing any transfers that aren't time critical and
bundling these with user initiated time critical transfers, or
those initiated from the server. If we compare the impact
on the radio of the big cookie model compared
to the previous on demand approach, you can see it's
now idle nearly two thirds of the time. Even
the active radio percentage has significantly dropped, thanks to improved
download efficiency as a result of transmitting more data in one shot